umw.edu 2018-12-26

# Internet Privacy Policy - Digital Communications

The following information explains the Internet Privacy Policy that the University of Mary Washington has adopted for our web site.

## Virginia Law

We protect our records in accordance with our obligations as defined by applicable Virginia statutes, including, but not limited to, the “Virginia Privacy Protection Act of 1976,” the “Virginia Freedom of Information Act,” and by any applicable U.S. federal laws.

## UMW Editorial Responsibility and Links to Other Web Sites

The University assumes editorial responsibility for official University of Mary Washington web sites and official UMW on-line resources, which are defined as the official web pages or on-line materials of UMW departments, divisions and other units. For these sites and resources, UMW is the content provider and not a content-neutral Internet Service Provider (ISP). You may also find within the UMW domain — signified by the address “umw.edu” or within the range of Internet protocol addresses assigned to the University — web sites or on-line materials over which the University has no editorial responsibility or control. Such sites include but are not limited to the web pages or other on-line materials of individual faculty members or students, individual class sites and materials, and the web pages or on-line materials of student organizations and other organizations not formally a part of the University. For these sites and materials, UMW is a content-neutral ISP and is not responsible for the content, privacy practices or policies of those who operate those sites.

Our web site may contain links to other public or private entities’ web sites. The University of Mary Washington is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites. It is recommended that users read the individual privacy policy statements of each web site when they leave a the University of Mary Washington server.

## Information We Collect

When you access the University of Mary Washington “official” web site(s), the routing (or client) information, along with essential and nonessential technical information listed below, is automatically collected. No other information is collected through our web site except when you deliberately decide to send it to us (for example, by clicking on a link to send us an email). The information you might choose to send us is listed below as “optional information.”

Routing, or client, information: The Internet domain and Internet address of the computer you are using.

Essential technical information: Identification of the page or service you are requesting, type of browser and operating system you are using; and the date and time of access.

Nonessential technical information. The Internet address of the web site from which you linked directly to our web site, and the “cookie information” as described below.

Optional information. When you send us an email, your name, email address, and the content of your email; when you fill out online forms, all the data you choose to fill in or confirm; and data that you choose to send to Administrative Systems is stored in a secure environment, protected from unauthorized access or disclosure. For those applications that process credit card payments, credit card number and expiration date are encrypted using a secure server for maximum security. Credit card numbers are stored on servers that are inaccessible from the Internet.

Cookies. Our web site may place a “cookie” on your computer, unless your browser is set to reject cookies. These cookies enable our web site to recognize you when you return to the web site at a later date or time and enables us to personalize the web site with preferences or information you have provided during prior sessions. The cookie information placed on your computer could include the following: IP address, browser type, operating system, the date and time, whether or not you have visited a web site before, where you went when you visited that web site, and any preferences or customization that you might have set (including username and passwords).

## How the Collected Information is Used

Routing information is used to route the requested web page to your computer for viewing. We send the requested web page and the routing information to our Internet service provider or other entities involved in transmitting the requested page to you. We do not control the privacy practices of those entities. Essential and nonessential technical information helps us respond to your request in an appropriate format, or in a personalized manner, and helps us plan web site improvements.

Optional information enables us to provide services or information tailored more specifically to your needs or to forward your message or inquiry to another entity that is better able to do so, and also allows us to plan web site improvements.

We may keep your information indefinitely, but we ordinarily delete the transaction routing information from our web server within 60 days after the web page is transmitted and do not try to obtain any information to link it to the individuals who browse our web site. However, on rare occasions when a “hacker” attempts to breach computer security, logs of routing information are retained to permit a security investigation and in such cases may be forwarded together with any other relevant information in our possession to law enforcement agencies. We use this transaction routing information primarily in a statistical summary type format to assess site content and server performance. We may share this summary information with our business partners when needed.

Optional information is retained in accordance with the records retention schedules at the Library of Virginia.

Under the “Virginia Freedom of Information Act,” any records in our possession at the time of a “Freedom of Information Request” might be subject to being inspected by, or disclosed to, members of the public. However, all identifiable confidential/personal information will be removed prior to releasing the routing information.

### **Online Advertising**

We use Google remarketing cookies on some admission-related sections of the website. These cookies allow us to customize advertising across the internet based on which parts of the website you visit. They do not identify you in any way.

You can opt out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting Google’s [Ads Settings](http://www.google.com/settings/ads). Alternatively, you can opt out of any third-party vendor’s use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

## Choice to Provide Information

There is no legal requirement for you to provide any information at our web site. However, our web site will not work without routing information and the essential technical information. Failure of your browser to provide nonessential technical information will not prevent your use of our web site, but may prevent certain features from working. Failure to provide optional information will mean that the particular feature or service associated with that part of the web page will be unavailable to you.

## Customer Comments or Review

If you have questions about this privacy statement or the practices of this web site, or if you choose to review or correct any information you previously submitted, please contact the webmaster.

##  

* * *

**_Last Updated:_** _August 7, 2018_
